velocityrewards.com.au 2008-04-09

# Velocity Rewards > Velocity Rewards Privacy Policy

Velocity Rewards Pty Ltd ACN 116 089 448 (“we”, “us”, and “our”) recognises the importance of privacy issues. This Privacy Policy briefly tells you how we manage the personal information that we collect, use and disclose and how to contact us if you have any queries. This Privacy Policy does not cover personal information collected or held by us about our employees and is to be read subject to any overriding provisions of law or contract. 

**Background**

Personal information is information or an opinion, in any form and whether true or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained from the information or opinion. 

There are special provisions which apply to the collection of some personal information which is known as sensitive information. This includes health information and information about a persons' race, ethnic origin, political opinions, membership of political, professional or trade associations, religious or philosophical beliefs, sexual preferences and criminal history. 

**Collection of personal information by us**

The kinds of personal information we collect and store will depend on what products and services you request from us or we provide to you. However, it may include (amongst other things): 

  * personal information you give us when you apply for membership of the Velocity Program. This information may include your name, mailing address, telephone numbers, e-mail address and date of birth ; 
  * information about transactions resulting in Points being earned or redeemed, and Rewards you receive; 
  * information about your Velocity Rewards Account, including the number of Points earned or redeemed; 
  * communications between you and us; and 
  * if you are applying for a position, we will collect information as outlined in the section below titled "Employment Applications". 

We may collect your personal information directly from you, or from third parties including our related entities, contractors, agents , Velocity Rewards Partners and other members of the Velocity Program. 

**Collection of personal information from children**

Where we collect personal information from a child (someone who we know is under 18 years of age), depending on the type of information we collect and how we intend to use it, we may ask the child to provide us with their parent's contact details. We will then seek their parent's consent to store, use and disclose the child's information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If we do not receive their parent's consent within a reasonable time, we will remove the child's personal information from our records. 

**How your personal information is stored**

We take reasonable steps to preserve the security of cookie and personal information. If your browser is suitably configured, it will advise you whether the information you are sending us will be secure (encrypted) or not secure (unencrypted). If secure transmission is indicated, we currently use 128 bit SSL encryption. 

We regularly review developments in security and encryption technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed as totally secure. Accordingly, although we strive to protect such information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we take reasonable steps to preserve the security of the information in our own systems. 

**How your personal information will be used**

We collect your personal information so that we can use it for our functions and activities, which include, amongst other things: 

  * administering the Velocity Program and providing products or services relating to the Velocity Program; 
  * planning, researching, developing, improving and promoting products or services offered by us or our related entities or any other organisation associated with the Velocity Program, including current and prospective Velocity Rewards Partners; 
  * processing and considering your employment application (refer to "Employment Application" section below); 
  * addressing any feedback or complaints you may have; 
  * answering any queries you may have; and 
  * any purposes for which it was requested and directly related purposes. 

If you do not provide us with your personal information, we will be unable to do one or more of the above (including being unable to process your membership application). 

We will assume you consent to management of your personal information in the manner specified in this Privacy Policy (which may change from time to time) until you tell us to the contrary by following the instructions contained in our website or contacting us using our contact details below. 

**Exchange of personal information with third parties**

Personal information we collect from you may be disclosed: 

  * to any entity to which we are required or authorised by or under law to disclose such information (for instance, law enforcement agencies and investigative agencies, courts, various other government bodies); 
  * to others that you have been informed of at the time any personal information is collected from you; 
  * to our related entities, contractors, agents or Velocity Rewards Partners for the purposes set out in the section above headed "How your personal information will be used", or for other purposes directly related to the purpose for which the personal information is collected; 
  * to our professional advisors and other contractors (for example IT consultants and mailing houses); or 
  * with your consent (express or implied), to others. 

Such disclosure may include the transfer of your personal information between countries. 

We may also obtain personal and other information from some or all of the above to enable us to provide our services or products to you. When we obtain personal and other information from third parties whom we are referred to by you, we will assume and you will ensure that you have made that third party aware of the referral of the persons and purposes involved in the collection, use and disclosure of the relevant personal or other information. 

**Use and disclosure of personal information by us**

If we use or disclose your personal information for a purpose (the "secondary purpose") other the main reason for which it was originally collected (the "primary purpose"), to the extent required by law, we will ensure that: 

  * the secondary purpose is related to the primary purpose of collection (and directly related in the case of sensitive information), and you would reasonably expect that we would use or disclose your information in that way; or 
  * you have consented to the use or disclosure of your personal information for the secondary purpose; or 
  * the use or disclosure is required or authorised by or under law; or 
  * the use or disclosure is otherwise permitted by law (for example, as a necessary part of an investigation of suspected unlawful activity). 

**Employment Applications**

If you apply for employment with us, then generally the type of personal information we collect about you is the information included in your application, for example, your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, career history, education details or other information relating to your career. 

In considering your application, we may also obtain personal information about you from third parties, for example, from your previous employers or nominated referees. We may also collect sensitive information about you such as information about your health (including any disability) or any criminal record that you may have. 

We collect personal information for any one or more of the following purposes: 

  * Assess you for a position or positions with us or our related entities; 
  * Assess whether you are suitable to progress to each stage of the recruitment process for a vacant position; or 
  * Store your information for future job opportunities. 

If you do not provide us with the information we seek, we will be unable to do one or more of the above. 

We may disclose your personal information to: 

  * organisations that conduct competency or psychometric tests; 
  * referees or previous employers; 
  * recruitment agencies or related entities acting on our behalf; 
  * our related entities; 
  * law enforcement agencies to verify whether you have a criminal record; or 
  * educational or vocational organisations to the extent necessary to verify your qualifications. 

If we engage third party contractors to perform services for us which involves handling personal information we will take reasonable steps to prohibit the contractor from using personal information except for the purposes for which it was supplied. 

**Collection of information other than personal information**

If you visit our website, some of the information we and/or our contractors collect about your visit to our website is not personal information because it does not reveal your identity. Information of this nature can include: 

  * Site visit information 
    * When you visit our website, we and/or our contractors collect general information about your visit which may include your server address, the date and time of your visit, the pages you accessed, the information you downloaded and the type of Internet browser you used. 
    * We and/or our contractors may use this information in anonymous, aggregated form, for statistical purposes only, to assist us in improving the quality and usability of our website. 
  * Cookies 
    * A cookie is a small string of information that a website transfers to your browser for identification purposes. The cookies we and/or our contractors use may identify individual users. 
    * Cookies can either be "persistent" or "session" based. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer, contain an expiration date, and are mainly for the user's convenience. Session cookies are short-lived and are held on your browser's memory only for the duration of your session, they are used only during a browsing session, and expire when you quit your browser. 
    * We and/or our contractors may use both session and persistent cookies. This information may be used to personalise your current visit to our and our contractors' websites. Upon closing your browser, the session cookie is destroyed. 
    * Most Internet browsers can be set to accept or reject cookies. If you do not want to accept cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to reject cookies or to notify you when they are being used. However, rejecting cookies may limit the functionality of our website. 

**Access and correction of your personal information**

You can ask to obtain access to your personal information that we hold, although under some circumstances permitted by law, we may not provide such information to you. Contact details for our related entities, contractors, agents and Velocity Rewards Partners are available from us upon request. 

We may ask you to put your request in writing and pay a reasonable fee levied by us for this. 

It is important to us that the personal information we hold about you is accurate, complete and up to date. If you are aware that this is not case and would like your personal information corrected, or simply desire access to your personal information, please contact our **Privacy Officer**. 

If we decide not to correct or provide you with access to your personal information, we will give you our reasons for our decision. 

**Site Security Policy**

Our website uses up-to-date technology to maximise the security of your personal information. Technology such as Secure Site Certificates and Secure Socket Layers ensure your information is secure as possible. We use a Thawte Secure Site Certificate to protect your personal information. Details and validity of this certificate can be viewed by clicking the thawte verification link in our **Website Security FAQ**. 

More information on Website Security can be found in our FAQ section and includes the topics below 

  * **What is SSL?**
  * **What are Cookies used for?**
  * **How can I maximise my Security Settings and still book redemption flights?**
  * **What is Velocity Rewards' Security Certification?**

**Complaints**

If you have a complaint about the way we have dealt with your personal information, please contact us at the above telephone numbers and ask to speak with our **Privacy Officer**. 

We will make all reasonable attempts to respond to your complaints or requests. 

**Updates to Privacy Policy**

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. If we do so, we will post the amended Privacy Policy on our website so that you will always be aware of how we manage your personal information. 

**Further information**

Please contact our **Privacy Officer** if you have any queries about the personal information that we hold about you or the way we handle that personal information. 

**Privacy Officer Contact Details**

The Privacy Officer  
Corporate Affairs Department  
Velocity Rewards Pty Ltd ACN 116 089 448   
PO Box 1034  
SPRING HILL QLD 4004  
AUSTRALIA 

Ph: +61 7 3295 3000  
Fax: +61 7 3839 4024  
Email: ******[privacy@velocityrewards.com.au](mailto:privacy@velocityrewards.com.au)**
